MYCHAL MARTINEZ

Denver, CO 80205 | 702.324.4947 | hello@mychalmartinez.com

Website: mychalmartinez.com | LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/mychalmartinez | GitHub: @milehighcoder

SUMMARY

Entrepreneurial-minded **Technical Project Manager** (Professional Scrum Master certification in progress) with over 8 years of business and program management experience. A certified web developer with an eye for design, exceptional technical aptitude, and the ability to perform in high-pressure environments. Seeking to make an impact with a company embodying the highest level of innovation, creativity, and culture.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programs: Photoshop, Final Cut Pro, Figma, Canva, WordPress, Google Analytics

Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Database & Libraries: mySOL, MongoDB, React.js, Bootstrap

Concepts: Visual Prototyping and Wireframing, User Experience and Interface Design, SEO Other: Heroku, Git, Command Line, Node.js, Express, APIs, REST, JSON, AJAX, Media Queries

EXPERIENCE

MYCHAL MARTINEZ BASKETBALL LLC

Nov 2016 to Present

Business Manager, Founder

Manages and executes in-person and virtual coaching programs for youth to high school level athletes.

- Has developed and mentored 25+ athletes that have successfully made the jump from high school to NCAA Division I/II/III collegiate athletics.
- Successfully pivoted a solely in-person coaching business into a hybrid web-based coaching platform in response to the COVID-19 outbreak ultimately leading to a significant increase in revenue.
- Developed a user-authenticated application using React. is that functions as a membership portal and allows clients exclusive access to virtual training content (via Youtube API) and the ability to book inperson workouts (via Google Calendar API).

COLORADO PREMIER BASKETBALL CLUB

Nov 2012 to Nov 2016

Program Manager, Co-Founder

Created work breakdown structures, documentation, schedules, budget/risk reports, and stakeholder engagement initiatives for the largest Nike-sponsored youth basketball club in the Rocky Mountain region.

- Drove an average of \$275,000 per year in membership revenue for middle and high school boys teams.

- Managed a staff of 20+ coaches, 2 program coordinators, and 15+ boys teams per year.

 Led and successfully closed a \$30,000 private sponsorship deal for low-income families within the club.

 Managed 80% of company web and digital content needs including 3 website redesigns, the development of a mobile application, and several SEO campaigns targeting the acquisition of new players.

EDUCATION

University of Denver Coding Boot Camp, Denver, CO

Mar 2021

Full Stack Web Development Certification

Scrum Master for Group Projects, A+ Student

University of Nevada Las Vegas, Las Vegas, NV

June 2012

Bachelor of Arts in Business Management, Audio Engineering

Basketball Team 2009-2011, Played in NCAA Tournament 2010 & 2011

Yavapai College, Prescott, AZ

May 2007

Associate of Arts in General Studies

Basketball Team 2007-2009, NJCAA Academic All-American